Great work today, everyone.
那麼 大家今天辛苦了
Cheers!
乾杯
Alcohol tastes great after a successful labyrinth raid.
攻略完迷宮喝的酒 果然超好喝的
Glad you like it.
妳喜歡就好
Is alcohol really that good?
酒真的有那麼好喝嗎
If you're curious,
好奇的話
why not take a sip?
要不要喝個幾口看看呀？
I've never heard that Homunculi can drink.
好像沒聽說過人造人可以喝酒
Is this okay?
這樣沒問題嗎
I really want to try...
好想喝喝看…
All right.
好吧
Just a little.
稍微喝一點 應該沒關係吧
Thank you very much.
謝謝您
It takes a while to get used to the taste.
剛開始喝酒的人 通常喝不習慣呢
Why did you make me try it then?
那您為什麼要勸我喝喝看呢
To see your reaction, of course.
因為這樣才能看到妳那種反應啊
It gets better after a few tries.
只要多喝幾次 就會漸漸覺得好喝囉
Enough about that.
好啦 先不談這件事了
You seem to be getting quite close to Lilia and Lily.
你最近好像跟莉莉亞她們 走得很近耶
I think we're about the same as we were before.
我覺得跟以前差不多啊
Really?
是嗎
What do you think, Luna?
露娜覺得呢
Hey. Don't drag Luna into this.
喂 別把露娜拉下水啊
I think you guys are close too.
我也…覺得你們的感情很好
Did that one sip get her drunk?
剛才那一口該不會害她醉了吧
That's not it.
不是
They're not our clan members,
她們雖然不是我們戰團的成員
but they helped us a lot too.
但她們也幫了我們很多忙吧
So,
所以
I was just worried
我只是擔心我們
if we'd cause them any trouble.
有沒有給她們添麻煩罷了
So, it's not a relationship beyond friendship?
所以你們不是超越夥伴的關係吧
Not at all.
完全不是
Then,
那麼
would you consider that kind of relationship with me?
你要跟我 成為那種關係嗎
Are you drunk?
妳是喝醉了嗎
Maybe.
或許吧
I've told you this before.
我之前應該也說過了
It's not something I'd consider at the moment.
我暫時不會考慮那種事
Raiding labyrinths is
現在對我來說最重要的 就是攻略迷宮
So, I'm not considering
所以現階段
that kind of relationship with anyone right now.
我不考慮跟任何人成為那種關係
That means we have to hurry up and settle all the matters.
那就得趕緊把這些事全都解決呢
Which means
也就是說
Master isn't seeing anyone right now?
主人現在沒有交往對象吧
Yes, that's right.
沒錯
Is something the matter?
怎麼了嗎
Being with Master
跟主人在一起時
always makes me very happy.
總是讓我非常開心
My heart can't help but feel warm.
內心也會不禁變得很溫暖
So, I want to be with Master forever.
所以我也想永遠和主人在一起
Is... Is that so?
這…這樣啊？
Rud, you're rather popular.
路德 你很受歡迎嘛
Shut up.
吵死了
Um,
那個
do you want some water?
妳要喝水嗎
Luna! Are you okay?
喂 露娜 妳沒事吧
-Looks like she's going to be a handful. -She's completely drunk.
-看來之後也會很辛苦呢 -根本已經醉得一塌糊塗了嘛
I feel drained...
總覺得今天特別疲憊呢
Huh? What?
呃
Lilia?
莉莉亞？
THE STRONGEST TANK'S LABYRINTH RAIDS
《最強肉盾的迷宮攻略～擁有稀少技能體力9999的肉盾，被勇者隊伍辭退了～》
Rud. Welcome back.
路德 歡迎回來
Wait, why are you sleeping on my bed?
不是 妳為什麼睡在我的床上啊
I had something I wanted to check on,
我有事想確認一下
so I asked Marius to let me come in and wait for you.
所以就拜託瑪里烏斯讓我進來等你
I'll leave you to the guard the room.
那就麻煩妳顧房間囉
I guess I'm more tired than I thought.
結果今天好像比想像中還累
I see.
原來如此
So, what did you need to talk to me about?
那妳是想跟我確認什麼事？
It's about Lily.
是關於莉莉今天的改變
She worked really hard today, didn't she?
那孩子 今天不是很努力嗎
Yes.
是啊
Lily performed better than I expected.
莉莉比我想像中還能幹
To be honest, she surprised me too.
老實說我也嚇了一跳
She's always been a kid who can do anything if she keeps cool.
她本來就是個只要保持冷靜 就什麼都辦得到的孩子
This is nothing.
那點小事根本不算什麼
You're twins, after all.
畢竟妳們是雙胞胎啊
It's not like there's a huge gap in your abilities.
看來在能力方面落差也不大呢
Lily's working really hard.
莉莉 真的很努力呢
She's trying to change, little by little.
一點一點地努力改變
Though maybe she overdid it today, she came back and collapsed from exhaustion.
雖然今天好像努力過頭 一回來就累癱了
What's wrong with you?
妳怎麼了？
What do you think about change?
那個 你怎麼看待"改變"這件事
Don't you find it scary?
不會覺得很可怕嗎
Well,
這個嘛
I actually don't like change much either.
我其實也不太喜歡改變
Especially recently,
尤其是最近
when Avancier started to change,
像是阿凡錫亞開始改變時
I felt like keeping things the same would be better.
我也會覺得保持原樣不是比較好嗎
I think many people in town probably share the same thought as me.
我想鎮上應該也很多人 跟我抱持一樣的想法
Even now,
就連我現在
I'm not sure if what I'm doing is right.
也不確定這麼做是不是正確的
But sometimes,
但是
I'm glad I embraced change.
我有時也會覺得幸好有去改變
If we had stayed the same,
畢竟如果一直保持原狀
we wouldn't see Avancier so lively and bustling now.
就看不到現在這般 充滿朝氣的阿凡錫亞
That's why I think
所以我認為
it's important to enjoy the change.
能享受變化才是最重要的
I've always thought it's best to keep things the way they are.
我一直都覺得 永遠維持現狀才是最好的
And I still do.
就連現在也是
Honestly, I'm weaker than Lily.
老實說 我比莉莉懦弱多了
Of course, I want to support her...
當然 我也想為那孩子加油
But watching Lily drift away from me makes me feel a little lonely.
只是 看著莉莉逐漸離我遠去 讓我覺得有些寂寞
Compared to Lily who wants to be independent,
比起想從姊姊身邊獨立的莉莉
Lilia, who can't be apart from her sister, might find it harder
無法離開妹妹的莉莉亞
to adapt to the change.
或許更難適應改變呢
Even though some things might change,
雖然有些事情改變了
I think
但是 我認為
you and Lily will always be the same.
莉莉亞和莉莉肯定不會有所改變
You two will always be close and love each other.
我覺得妳們今後也會一直 像現在這麼相親相愛
Even if some things change,
就算某些地方改變了
the important things won't.
根本的部分是不會改變的吧
So, even if other things change,
所以 就算其他地方改變了
you can still get along like you do now.
妳們還是能像現在這樣相處下去啊
You're unexpectedly thoughtful.
你意外地考慮得滿多的嘛
Well, sorry. I was only saying what came to mind.
抱歉啊 我只說得出腦中想到的事
No, that'll do.
不 這樣就夠了
That's what I needed to hear.
而且這正是我想聽到的
Lily was shining so brightly today.
今天的莉莉太耀眼了
I couldn't look at her at all.
讓我完全無法直視她
But
不過
starting tomorrow, I will be watching her
明天開始我會好好看著
do her best.
那孩子努力的身影
Go for it.
加油喔
I will.
我會加油的
"CAIRD LABYRINTH: FIRST FLOOR" Let's start from the 51st floor today.
(凱路德迷宮第1層) 那今天就從第51層開始吧
Lily, do the honours.
莉莉 拜託妳囉
Got it.
好的
The two major clans only made it to the 51st floor as well.
由於兩大戰團也才剛到51層
So we currently have no intel on this level.
目前還沒掌握到任何情報
However, the mist inside the labyrinth is thick.
但是迷宮裡的霧很濃
We should have other means to locate the monsters
我認為除了使用探知魔法之外
besides detection magic.
也需要用其他方式尋找魔物
In that case, Lily will continue to use detection magic.
那莉莉就照樣使用探知魔法
Marius and I will search for monsters within visible range.
瑪里烏斯和我 則在看得到的範圍內尋找魔物
Luna, stay on high alert at all times.
露娜也要隨時保持警戒
Okay.
好的
A… About yesterday,
昨…昨天的事是那個
I didn't mean anything.
總之 我沒有其他意思
Oh, okay.
這…這樣啊
Seems like Luna's the type that won't black out even after drinking.
看來露娜是那種喝醉後 也不會斷片的人呢
Ready, everyone?
那麼 各位都準備好了吧
"Dungeon Walk".
"迷宮傳送"
CAIRD LABYRINTH, 51ST FLOOR
(凱路德迷宮第51層)
The fog is really thick here.
這層的霧確實很濃厚呢
I don't think we can use detection magic in this area.
這裡好像沒辦法使用探知魔法
Luna,
露娜
can you try clearing the fog with wind magic?
妳可以試試看 能否用風魔法吹散霧嗎
Certainly.
好的
It didn't work.
不行嗎
This fog
這個霧
was created by magic.
恐怕是用魔力創造出來的
What?
什麼
That's why it won't disperse even if you use wind.
所以就算用風吹也吹不散
However,
不過
all monsters have some magic on them.
魔物身上總會有魔力
Just focus on detecting that energy.
只要專心探測魔力就可以了
I'll try.
我試試看
It's not exact, but I can vaguely sense it.
雖然不是很完美 但多少察覺得到
It's coming.
要來了
Everyone, get back.
大家快站到我身後
Something's coming!
有東西要來了
"Taunt"!
"挑釁"
Water magic?
是水魔法嗎
This looks like...
這樣看來
The enemy is likely a Sahuagin!
對手應該是半魚人
I'll dispel them.
我來驅散他們
It's too foggy. Our vision is obstructed.
霧實在太濃了 看不見敵人有些棘手呢
Everyone,
各位
move to the ten o'clock direction.
逃到十點鐘方向
That area isn't surrounded by the fog yet.
那邊還沒有被包圍
Leave it to me.
交給我吧
"Taunt"!
"挑釁"
Finally coming out of the fog.
終於從霧裡出來了嗎
Just like Lily said.
跟莉莉說的一樣
It's a Sahuagin.
應該是半魚人
Even if I can't see with my eyes, I can find you guys
就算雙眼都看不到 我也可以用探知能力
by detecting your energy.
找到你們
Nice job, Marius.
幹得好 瑪里烏斯
After that,
後來
we mastered the detection technique
我們漸漸掌握到瑪里烏斯說的
Marius taught us
探測魔物魔力的訣竅
and successfully defeated all the Sahuagin.
順利打倒後來出現的半魚人們
Let's take a break before heading to the next floor.
前往下一層前 先休息一下吧
I'll cook us something.
那我來煮個飯吧
We'll help.
我也來幫忙
You guys are going to eat the Sahuagin?
你們要吃半魚人嗎
Yes.
對啊
We have to use this chance to replenish our energy.
得趁現在補充能量才行
Speaking of which,
話說回來
the items we got from this drop are quite something.
這次掉下來的素材全都很驚人呢
Right.
對啊
This is high-quality stuff.
全是些高級品
I can finally look Lily in the eye like I usually do.
我今天總算可以 像平時那樣直視莉莉了
Thanks to our talk last night.
這都是因為昨天有跟你聊過的關係
Thank you.
謝謝你
You two, food is ready.
你們兩個 飯煮好囉
Sahuagin tastes great!
半魚人好好吃
No fog here, but this place is spacious.
雖然沒有霧 但這裡很寬敞呢
Looks like a place where a boss would appear.
簡直就像頭目的房間
Enemy approaching.
敵人好像來囉
A magic circle?
魔法陣？
It's a Dark Skeleton.
是黑暗骷髏
There's something else too.
好像還有其他東西
Something we haven't seen before.
是之前沒看過的東西呢
Blue, red, yellow.
藍色 紅色 黃色
They look like crystals.
看起來就像水晶一樣
"Sacrificial Shield".
"犧牲之盾"
Such a powerful aura.
好強大的威壓
It's unlike any opponent
他跟我們至今對戰過的對手
we've faced so far.
完全不能相提並論
Lily, please give instructions.
莉莉 麻煩妳下達指示
I'll start with physical attacks.
我先用撞擊的方式攻擊他
Understood.
好的
"Taunt"!
"挑釁"
What?
什麼
It's the crystal.
是水晶
When Rud attacked, the yellow crystal unleashed
黃色的水晶隨著路德發動攻擊
a protective shield.
展開了類似防護罩的東西
This is a tricky foe.
真棘手啊
Should I put some distance between us for now?
要暫時拉開距離嗎
So the red one is offensive.
紅色是用來攻擊的嗎
Then, the blue one is…
那藍色是…
Its movements became faster.
他的動作變快了
I see.
原來如此
The yellow one acts as a tank for defence,
黃色會像肉盾一樣進行防禦
the blue one enhances abilities,
藍色是強化能力
and the red one is for magical attacks.
紅色則是魔法攻擊
This is a tricky monster we're up against.
真是隻難纏的魔物啊
Among them, the yellow defence crystal is the biggest problem.
其中黃色的防護罩是最棘手的
How should we attack?
該怎麼進攻才好呢
For now,
總之先像平時那樣
I'll attract its attention
把他的注意力吸引過來
and then attack from behind.
再從後方進行攻擊
Our attacks were blocked.
被擋下了
But it seems it can only deploy the shield around the crystals.
但他好像只能 在水晶周圍展開防護罩
Great, that'll work.
很好 行得通
Continue attacking it like this.
就這樣繼續攻擊他
A distraction?
是障眼法嗎
Is everyone all right?
大家沒事吧
Marius, what's wrong?
瑪里烏斯 你怎麼了
I'm fine. It's Lilia…
我沒事 是莉莉亞…
Something's not right with her.
莉莉亞看起來有些奇怪
Lilia, what's wrong?
莉莉亞 妳怎麼了啊
Don't…
不准…
Don't bully Lily!
不准欺負莉莉
I must protect her.
我得保護她才行
Lily!
莉莉
You've got me into trouble again.
妳又給我捅婁子
Lilia!
莉莉亞
I have to protect her.
我得保護她才行
Don't bully Lily!
不准欺負莉莉
I will
莉莉
protect her…
就由我…
I'm your father.
我可是妳老爸
What's with that look?
妳那是什麼眼神
Someone...
誰來…
-help us... -You guys are such an eyesore.
-救救我們 -妳們真的很礙眼耶
I won't let you bully Lily anymore!
不准你再繼續欺負莉莉
Nin, heal her.
妮恩 快幫她回復
Hold on.
等一下
Lily and Luna were afflicted too.
莉莉她們也陷入異常狀態了
I have to heal them first.
我先治療她們兩個
Got it.
我知道了
I see.
原來如此
Only Marius, Nin, and I
有異常狀態抗性
are immune to abnormal status ailments.
只有我和瑪里烏斯和妮恩
If the entire party falls into abnormal status,
如果全員都陷入異常狀態
we'll be wiped out.
我們可能就全軍覆沒了
"Life Conversion"!
"生命轉換"
You sent it flying with the crystals. Impressive.
居然能連同水晶把他揍飛 真有你的
Marius,
瑪里烏斯
can you hold the Dark Skeleton back?
你能負責壓制黑暗骷髏嗎
Leave it to me.
交給我吧
That thing's a lot easier to deal with.
那邊好應付多了
Lilia!
莉莉亞
I'm sorry, Lilia.
抱歉了 莉莉亞
-Lilia, you need to calm down. -Let go of me!
-莉莉亞 妳冷靜一點 -放開我
I won't let you bully Lily anymore!
不准你再繼續欺負莉莉
Don't bully Lily!
不准欺負莉莉
You said you were abandoned by your parents
妳說妳們被父母拋棄
and have been travelling with only each other since.
是靠互相扶持才走到現在的
Well,
不
rather than say we were abandoned,
與其說是被拋棄
it would be more accurate to say we ran away
正確來說 其實是因為父母會虐待我們
because we were being abused.
所以我們才從那邊逃走了
Did the abnormal status
難道她的異常狀態
trigger her past trauma?
是會看到過去的心理創傷嗎
If I remember correctly, it's possible to calm down
我記得面對恐慌狀態的人
someone that's panicking by reassuring them with words
只要跟她說一些 能排除恐慌因素的話
that can dispel the cause.
就能恢復正常
Lilia,
莉莉亞
no one is going to hurt you here.
這裡沒有人會欺負妳們
Don't worry.
放心吧
You two are strong now.
妳們已經變強了
Ru…Rud?
路…路德？
That's right. It's me, Rud.
沒錯 我是路德
Everyone is here.
我和其他夥伴都在這裡
So calm down.
所以 妳冷靜一點
No matter what happens,
不論發生什麼事
I'll do my best to protect you both.
我都會竭盡全力保護妳們的
I…
我…
The Dark Skeleton's magic must have thrown you
妳應該是受到黑暗骷髏的魔法影響
into a state of confusion.
陷入混亂了
Don't worry.
別擔心
There's plenty of people
現在有很多人
that will help you now.
都會幫助妳了吧
You're right.
你說得對
I have Rud and everyone else.
我現在有路德和其他夥伴了
Marius, thanks for holding it off.
瑪里烏斯 辛苦你撐到現在了
Take a break and get yourself healed.
暫時退下 去接受治療吧
This is nothing.
這點程度根本不算什麼
But roger that.
不過我就聽你的吧
We won't be able to seriously damage it
果然 如果不先破壞掉黃色水晶
unless we destroy the yellow crystal.
就沒辦法痛快地打一場
But if we can break it,
不過反過來說 只要能突破那一點
we can finish this.
就沒問題了吧
It's trying to trap me.
看來他想把我困在這裡
In that case...
既然如此
Nin,
妮恩
I need your support.
麻煩妳了
This will give me some protection from the fire magic.
這下就能稍微抵擋住火魔法了
The crystals switch too quickly!
水晶的切換速度好快
Is there really no other way?
果然沒轍了嗎
Lilia, Marius,
莉莉亞 瑪里烏斯
I think I found an opening.
我好像找到突破方法了
The water droplets on my body
剛才附著在我身上的水滴
went through its protective shield
穿過防護罩
and landed on the Dark Skeleton.
滴到了黑暗骷髏的身上
I'm guessing this thing
我猜這傢伙
can't resist both physical and magical attacks at once.
應該沒辦法同時抵擋 魔法和物理攻擊
It's worth a shot.
確實值得一試呢
The fire magic penetrated through the shield!
火魔法穿過防護罩了
This is payback for earlier.
這是你讓我陷入恐慌狀態的回禮
It blocked our attacks,
雖然被擋下了
but we managed to damage it.
但我們確實對他造成傷害了
Let's keep this up!
繼續加油吧
It's no use.
沒用的
You won't get us with that trick again.
這邊已經沒有人會被那招影響了
Because I've used my magic
因為我用魔法
to nullify the effects of all abnormal statuses.
讓異常狀態無效化了
Luna's wind magic.
露娜的風魔法
Nin's water magic.
妮恩的水魔法
Lily's fire magic.
莉莉的火魔法
It's incredible.
這畫面真驚人呢
The yellow crystal is glowing!
黃色水晶發光了
It's trying to activate the shield and escape!
他打算展開防護罩逃跑
Rud?
路德
You'll be damaged by our magic attacks.
你會被我們的魔法波及到的
I'll convert the damage
那些傷害
into power using "Life Conversion".
正好可以用"生命轉換" 換成攻擊力
"Life Conversion"!
"生命轉換"
It's been weakened.
他確實變弱了
It split into two!
居然分裂了
Even the crystals duplicated.
連水晶都變多了
Lilia, Marius,
莉莉亞 瑪里烏斯
take one.
你們先幫我打倒一隻
But we don't know which is the real one.
但是 我不知道哪隻才是真的
Any one will do.
隨便一隻都可以
Rud won't be able to hold out much longer.
這樣下去路德會撐不住的
That's the real one!
那一隻才是真的
Its reaction is completely different from earlier.
他的反應跟剛才完全不一樣
In that case…
那麼…
This is the final blow.
這就是 最後一擊
Marius, Lilia,
瑪里烏斯 莉莉亞
take it down!
打倒他
I thought it was over for us
頭目突然出現時
when the boss suddenly spawned.
我還以為完蛋了呢
I need a break.
但我已經累到想休息一下了
Yeah.
是啊
Let's hurry up and find the magic circle
趕緊找到魔法陣
and get to the next floor so we can rest.
在前往下一層前 先休息一下吧
I'll use my detection magic to find it.
那我用探知魔法找
The fog isn't too thick here, so it should work.
這裡的霧不濃 應該行得通
That's strange.
奇怪
What's wrong?
怎麼了
I can't locate the magic circle.
找不到魔法陣
I can't sense it at all.
簡直一點氣息都沒有
Is this
難道
the final floor?
這裡就是最底層了嗎
Marius, what do you think?
瑪里烏斯 你怎麼看
Honestly,
老實說
I haven't the faintest clue what the guardian here is trying to do.
我完全搞不懂 這裡的守護者在想什麼
Maybe that Dark Skeleton was their masterpiece
搞不好剛才那隻黑暗骷髏 就是他的完美傑作
and seeing us defeat it scared them off.
看到我們將他打敗 守護者就怕到不敢出來了
So they sealed off the way to stop us from advancing?
所以才把下一層的通道封起來了嗎
Yes.
沒錯
I don't think
我覺得這裡的守護者
this is an ordinary guardian we're dealing with.
應該不是普通人
So this is as far as we can go?
也就是說 我們只能攻略到這裡了嗎
Still, we've made it far enough.
不過目前的戰績應該已經夠了
Let's head back for now.
還是就先回去吧
Aw.
什麼嘛
Are you already turning back?
你們要回去了嗎
Who's there?
是誰
She's emitting such an intense aura... Who is this girl?
這個散發著奇妙壓迫感的 少女是怎麼回事
Rud, this is bad!
路德 大事不妙了
Oh, dear.
搞什麼
Did I set it so that Dark Skeletons would continue to spawn?
這裡的設定 是會繼續出現黑暗骷髏嗎
Set?
設定？
If we get attacked by four of them at once...
在這邊一次遭到四隻攻擊的話…
I thought I'd already disabled that.
我應該已經改掉了啊
She took all of them down in one hit.
居然一擊就打倒了
I didn't expect
沒想到
a demon lord-class guardian would appear.
居然會出現魔王等級的守護者